People want to marry for love.
If you read the Bible very well,
people marry for purpose,
not for love. Positioning for
stratospheric influence.
Right? Positioning for stratospheric
influence.
>> [snorts]
>> So, the question is how does God work
through marriages,
right? To achieve his purposes for the
end time. How does God work through us,
through our through our lives, through
our statuses
to achieve his own purposes? We're going
to be going through a lot in the course
of this conversation and I trust God
that is going to reach out to each one
of us in Jesus' name. So, let me start
this with a short story from one of my
favorite series, right? So, in Game of
Thrones season 7, episode 7,
right? So,
it was the time when Jon Snow and some
and Tyrion Lannister Tyrion Lannister,
they went to Cersei and they were going
to seek the help of King's Landing in
the fight against the dead. We know Jon
Snow's character was a very plain guy.
So, of course, he would he just said
things the way they were and then Tyrion
was furious. He said, "Guy, at least you
should be able to make with some lies
sometimes. You know my sister." Then,
Jon Snow said something which
I want us to listen to. He said, "When
enough people make false promises,
words stop meaning nothing.
There are no more answers, only better
and better lies.
And lies cannot help us in this fight."
Whether we like it or not, there is a
constant fight between light and
darkness.
And now that we have perfected the art
of storytelling, it is no longer about
who is telling the truth, but who is
showing up consistently and sharing
their own truth.
So, even when it looks like what they
are saying we don't agree with it, but
because they show up consistently, they
show up boldly, courageously, we begin
to to believe them.
Now, thinking that we need what they
have, we then lose sight of the things
that we have. In losing sight of the
things that we that we have, chasing
what we think they have, not only do we
lose what we possess, but we also lose
our place and our position in God.
So, the question then is, why are we
having this conversation tonight?
The three things the three reasons why I
am talking to us tonight, number one is
the finality of God's word.
Number two is that God is aware of your
status and he wants to use it.
God is aware of your status and he wants
to use it.
And the third reason is to encourage you
to remain anchored in your position in
God as a role model to your tribe and to
your generation.
Because if we don't pay attention that
in the midst of whatever you think you
are going through that eyes have not
seen that ears have not heard like we
say in our part of the world, we have
never heard of this before. We are only
scaring the person. There's nothing new
under the sun, the Bible says. Nothing
new. Nothing. Ecclesiastes um uh 1:11
1:9. There's nothing new under the sun.
Right? So, when we have this
understanding, then it helps us to be
better positioned wherever we are, no
matter our status, and God can then
freely work in us, with us, and through
us to shine his light to our tribe and
to our generation. And my prayer is that
in the course of this conversation, God
will reach out to someone specifically
tonight and it will deliver to you his
blueprint, his plan, his promises for
you and your generation in Jesus' name.
Let's read Genesis chapter 3.
Right, because we live in a world now
where people are asking a lot of
questions. Right, so uh uh uh
we are everything we we we have a
generation that questions everything.
You know, uh
some generations are fading away and
then we have the the Gen Zs, the Gen
Alphas, the Gen Betas developing at the
same time and one of the characteristics
of these three newest generations is the
fact that they like to ask questions.
So, let's look at the first set of
questions that were asked in the Bible,
the first three questions. It will help
us to have an understanding of how the
world operates. Because when it looks
like we are losing touch of what is
going on, the best thing is to press
reset. You go back to the beginning, how
it all started from. And and and for me,
I I just love Genesis, right? So, let's
look at Genesis chapter 3.
I'm going to read I'm reading AMPC.
Genesis chapter 3 verse 1 and then I
will jump to verse 6.
AMPC. Now, the serpent was more subtle
and crafty than any living creature of
the field which the Lord God had made.
And he, Satan, said to the woman,
"Can it really be
that God has said,
'Can it really be that God has said,
"You shall not eat from every tree of
the garden?" Let's jump to verse 6.
And when the woman saw
that the tree was good, suitable,
pleasant for food, and that it was
delightful to look at, and a tree to be
desired in order to make one wise. She
took of his fruit and ate, and she gave
some also to her husband, and he ate.
Then the eyes of them both were opened,
and they knew that they were naked, and
they sewed fig leaves together and made
themselves apron-like girdles. And they
heard sound of the Lord God walking in
the garden in the cool of the day, and
Adam and his wife hid themselves from
the presence of the Lord God among the
trees of the garden.
But the Lord God called to Adam and said
to him, "Where are you?"
He said, "I heard the sound of you
walking in the garden, and I was afraid
because I was naked, and I hid myself."
And he said,
"Who told you?
Who told you that you were naked?
Have you eaten of the tree of which I
commanded you that you should not eat?"
So, three important questions for our
meditation tonight as we go in this
discourse. The first one, did God really
say
One of the questions that generations
upon generation are asking is, "Did God
really say
that I cannot
Did God really say?" You know, so in the
course of my preparation, I I did a
little bit of empirical research, right?
I I asked questions from different
people because I know that my own
experience cannot be enough to address
everybody, right? So, I I asked people
different people questions from our
church. Um in all, I should have about
an audience of 70. So, you know that
everything I'm going to say is not just
my own experience, but some other
people's experiences, too. So, I'll be
uh borrowing from what they shared with
me and then I'll be slotting it where
applicable. You know, but the question
is
are we asking
did God really say?
Did God really say?
Did God really say
that
uh so, let me share one of the stories.
Um
so, there is one of our members, you
know,
um beautiful couple, amazing couple.
Um
they've been married now for about 30
years, you know.
And then, so when I I told her that I'm
going to do this, she said, "Okay,
Pastor." In fact, she said, "You know
what? I've also been thinking of having
a podcast around this topic." So, I
said, "Please, ma, can you share your
experience? How was it like?"
Um you know, she said when they
discovered that they were not going to
have children.
Uh she said it was of course a
devastating moment for them.
>> [snorts]
>> And then,
um they had a lot of things they were
considering and all of that.
But, at some point, they decided they
were going to adopt.
Um and then, when the adoption thing was
going to happen, it was a whole lot of
issues. But, she she said she had peace,
so she wasn't going to play the Nigerian
drama because they wanted them to, you
know, you know how it is, pay your way.
She said, "No, God said we should do
this." So, he said they just left the
matter. A few weeks after,
you know, um she got a call from one of
the agencies that they found a a boy and
that she should come and check. And when
they saw him, she said, "Wow, this is
the our son. This is the person we've
been looking for." You know, and then,
she said that so, she now has a
foundation that reaches out to people
who are in their waiting season.
Right? Which is what we're are talking
about, positioning for stratospheric
influence. God knows where you are. He
knows your status, and he wants to use
it. And then, I asked her a question. I
said, "What do you think about a woman
who says, 'Well,
um I'm of age. Nobody is coming. Can't I
just go for artificial insemination, get
myself, you know, pregnant, and all of
that?'" And she said,
"Pastor, I I'm starting a podcast on
that thing." She said, "They we we had a
thought around it, but then we looked at
the scriptures, and then one of the
things we realized is that God ideally
want every child to be raised in a
family."
She said, "That's why uh um
uh I will not advise anyone to go that
route, because the question is, 'What is
the person looking at?'" Now, I'm using
her word, not mine.
Now, she said, "What is the person
thinking of? Are they thinking of the
child? Are they thinking of God? Or are
they thinking of themselves?"
Right? So, these are questions upon many
people's hearts. Somebody might be
thinking, "So, why can't I do this? Did
God really say I can't do this? Did God
really say?" Then another question is,
uh you know, someone said, "Did God
really say that I cannot have someone
outside if I am no longer being
satisfied? You know, if my wife no
longer satisfies me." Right?
Can I Can I do something? Did God really
say?
You know, and then one of the persons I
interviewed, in fact, that one was a
timely one. So, we started talking, and
then we started sharing about the fact
that, "See, this is what God says about
covenant, honoring the the the vow." The
Bible says that uh um
that the bed on the vow, you know, and
by the time we're done, he said,
"Pastor, you don't know what you have
just done for me. You just delivered me.
I have been thinking that this old
arrangement is not working, and I was
going to help myself."
You know, and that was how a marriage
was restored.
A casual conversation that was
deliverance for someone.
Right? So, the question I am posing to
us today, the same question Satan asked
Eve, is this did God really say? I know
many of us you can apply to any aspect
of your life, but I know you have been
asking some questions. Did God really
say?
Did God really say? Whenever you find
yourself questioning your own
convictions, it's two things. It's
either God wants to create the next
level from where you are, or Satan is
working on your mind. Let me say that
again. Every time you question your
beliefs,
questioning beliefs is not a bad thing
in itself, but the question is, every
time you question your belief, it's
either God wants to open your eyes to
see the next level of that thing, or
Satan is somewhere lurking around to
bring you down.
Did somebody hear that? So, the question
is, why is this speaker like this?
Why can't we
Did Did you understand that? Once you
begin to question the imperfection in
anything, that means that there is a
next level coming out. But, the danger
of it is that you also need to ask
yourself who is inspiring that question.
Did you Did we get that? Who is
inspiring the question? Because the next
question God asked, you know, after
where are you, God said, "Who told you?"
Are we on the same page? Who told you?
Who inspired the information that that
that propelled your action? That
compelled your action. Who inspired it?
Who told you? Very critical.
You know, when you look at that
conversation, there's something I
created. I call it the power action
cycle.
Right? The first thing is distraction.
You know, I realized from um the the
garden that there's actually media in
the garden.
What is media? Television and uh social
media. Something that you watch.
You experience it, but you cannot touch
it. You can't partake in it, right? So,
God put a tree in the garden. They call
it the tree of knowledge and evil. So,
you can look at it, too. You can touch
it, too, but you must not eat it.
Right?
And then, if we keep going around the
garden, and we're listening.
And then,
and then one day, the Bible said she
saw. See, when you look at something
long enough, you will see.
She saw.
When See, when you look at something
long enough, remember what I said.
Either it is God inspiring what you are
seeing, or it is Satan inspiring what
you are seeing. But one important thing
is, if you look at something long
enough, you will see.
The Bible said, seek and you shall
So, it is a It is a practical law.
Seek and you shall find. You will seek
what you are looking for. You will find
what you are looking for.
Trust me.
She was just whistling one morning.
>> [whistles]
>> Who knows that song? Dun na na na na na
na na
So, wow, look at this tree.
And then the Bible says she saw Now, she
has never tasted it. The Bible says she
saw
that it is good for food.
She has never tasted it.
And that it is desirable to make one
wise.
She saw See, when you pay attention long
enough, you will see.
When you look long enough, you will see.
But the question is, who is inspiring
what you are seeing or what you seek in
the first place?
Very critical.
Be- because really God wants to work
through us as a church. He wants to work
through us as a people. So, asking
questions itself is not a problem.
But the question is, who is inspiring
the questions you are asking?
That's why God asked them,
"Who told you?"
"Who told you that you were naked? Who
told you?" So, if you look at what
happened, eventually they saw that they
were not complete. They saw that
something was missing in their lives.
Every time you look away from God, what
you see are your inadequacies.
Every time you look away from God, you
no longer depend on his strength.
What you then see are your own
weaknesses and your inadequacies. And
that was exactly what happened. Say,
"Oh, we are naked." And then they
started making, you know, arches.
In the midst of that,
in the midst of their errors,
see what God did. God said, "If you use
leaves, after a few days, it's going to
decay."
So, what God did, God performed a
sacrifice.
Killed an animal.
And then brought the skin to them and
said, "Guys, use this to cover
yourself."
Why? Because you have just lost uh you
have just lost your position as my
ambassador, but you have not lost your
place as my son.
Let me say that again.
When we walk out of God's will as
Christians, as children of God,
we may not necessarily lose our sonship,
not necessarily lose our focus, our walk
with him, but something happened in that
place.
They lost their ambassadorial
assignment.
And that was why God said, "You no
longer qualify to be in this domain."
And God moved them out.
They lost their ambassadorial
assignment, but they did not lose their
place as sons and daughters of God. Did
somebody hear what I said?
Right. So, because sometimes when we
begin to walk in disobedience, I said
I'm going to say something about what I
call the power action cycle. The first
way, how does Satan get us out of track?
The first thing is distraction.
Is distraction.
You will just begin to look for
something that is not lost.
Distraction.
And once distraction enters, the next
thing is doubt.
Doubt means you then begin to ask
questions. You begin to question the
things that you once believed. And once
doubt enters, you enter to the realm of
difference. At the point of difference,
your will is broken. At that point,
anything enters, anything goes.
When you enter from difference, then you
go into doing the actual thing.
And from doing the last one, which devil
is looking for, is displacement.
Is displacement. So, you go from
destruction to doubt to difference
to doing
and then to displacement.
Whatever it is, what Satan is looking
for is to make sure you lose your place.
Now,
with all the distractions that has hit
the church in recent times, we now call
this generation the post-church world.
You know what that means? That means
that the church has lost the kind of
voice and relevance and significance
that the church used to have.
Today, many of us pastors don't like to
introduce ourselves as pastors anymore.
How many of you How many of you know
what I'm talking about? Because once we
hear bro like this, your defense just
goes off. Ah, bro, you know, ah,
bro,
bro, sis, right? Why? Because
it's looking like the people who call
themselves by that uh appellation no
longer understand what it means to be a
brother.
When I was growing up, there are some
people we called SU.
One of the characteristics of those
people is the fact that they their yes
is their yes, their no is their no.
These are people that you look at, even
though we did not like them, we named
them, we
In fact, before I got born again, we
called them Scripture Union.
We called them names, but one of the
things you cannot take away from those
group was the fact that their yes is
yes, their no is no.
But how many Christians do we have today
that you can stand your ground and say,
"Look, if I say white, it is white, not
off-white,
not a shade of gray.
White is white." How many Christians do
we have today who can stand their own?
And God is still looking for people
that he can use, that he can send, that
can be his voice.
No matter your status,
because each status represents a tribe.
Whether you are married, you are single,
you are divorced, separated, you are
widowed, it you represent a tribe.
And sometimes, if we pay enough
attention, God can work in that
situation
to still achieve his purposes, only if
we are willing, yielding, obedient. Like
he said, Isaiah 1:19, "If you are
willing and obedient, you will eat the
good of the land."
So, [snorts] how do you position
yourself in spite of
your status? Whether you are married,
you are single, you know, let me quickly
say this.
You know,
um
there was this time I I did a course on
um you know,
um family systems and all of that. And
in the course of my study that period,
that was around 2017, one of the things
I realized
is that
you know that one of the greatest
distractions of the church today
is that people want to marry for love.
If you read the Bible very well,
people marry for purpose,
not for love.
One of the things that is keeping the
monarchical system in a country like UK
till today is marriage.
When we cross to the other side, ask
Diana.
It's marriage.
So,
we don't understand assignment.
And many of us, we just say, "Oh, I love
you. I love you." It is after we are
falling in love that we are now trying
to look for assignment.
So, okay, let me I'm entering into Okay,
so, now, how do you position yourself
for stratospheric influence? No matter
how your status, let me let's talk about
these three things. So, I've I've
mentioned the first one, assignment.
So, three things I'll talk about, your
assignment,
your authority, and accountability.
Those three things, very critical.
So, let's talk Let's look at assignment.
Let's read Genesis
Genesis chapter 1.
I'm still reading AMPC.
I know uh my colleague said a little bit
about it um last week. If you missed
that message, you should
go check it out.
So, let me write on where he stopped.
Genesis chapter uh
Okay, so I've covered a much Okay,
Genesis 1:26 to 28 AMPC.
The Bible says, "God said, 'Let us,
Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, make
mankind in our image after our likeness.
And let them have complete authority
over the fish of the sea, the birds of
the air, the tame beasts, and over all
of the earth, and over everything that
creeps upon the earth.'
So, God created man in his own image, in
the image and likeness of God he created
him. Male and female he created them.
And God blessed them and said to them,
"Be fruitful, multiply, and fill the
earth, and subdue it using all its vast
resources in the service of God and man.
And have dominion over the fish of the
sea, the birds of the earth, and over
every living creature that moves upon
the earth. Let me add one Bible verse to
it and then I'll I'll I'll explain.
Judges chapter 4 verse 4 because I want
to address the women folk tonight.
Judges 4 verse 4, easy to read version.
ERV. The Bible says there was a woman
a woman prophet named Deborah.
She was the wife of a man named
Lapidoth. She was judge of Israel at
that time.
Now,
reading through Genesis 1:26-28,
very critical.
So, I strongly believe that there are
three roles you can play effectively
when it comes to this issue of marriage
and purpose
in life.
One of them, you don't choose. You found
You just find yourself in it.
The other two is a choice.
You are either a man or a woman.
No shades in between.
Amen, somebody.
According to scriptures,
you are either a man or a woman.
The other choices you have
is to be a husband or a wife.
It's a choice.
And then the other
addition to it is to be a father
or a mother.
You don't choose whether you are going
to be a man or a woman.
But being a husband or wife or mother or
father many times is not within our
control.
Did you hear what I said?
Being a husband or wife
or being a mother or a father sometimes
are not within our control. But there is
one God has given us control over.
That is manhood and womanhood. Your best
gift to the world is your manhood and
your womanhood. That's your best gift to
the world because that is who God
created you to be from the beginning.
And how do you demonstrate that you are
a man? How do you demonstrate that you
are a woman? God has said it here. He
said,
"Take charge of the earth. Use its vast
resources to be a blessing to humanity."
Focus on what I have called you to do.
That was the first and primary
assignment that God gave the first set
of humans that he created.
So, when we go back to the beginning,
then we understand that manhood and
womanhood are very critical to our
existence.
So, what then happens is that when it
looks like wifehood is not happening or
husbandhood is not happening, many of us
then get distracted. We feel that if I
am not a husband or I'm not a wife, I
cannot be complete.
Are we on the same page? And in looking
for what we think will make us complete,
then we lose sight of the primary thing
that God has called us to be.
Which is being a woman or being
a man.
You know, and and why I I I just feel
like encouraging our women folk tonight,
you know, we will never have known that
there was a man called Lapidoth
in the Bible
if not because there was one woman who
went against the tides. Now, remember
the culture of the people who wrote the
Bible. They were male. I don't want to
call them male chauvinist.
But you know, it was a male-dominated
society.
So, unless a woman has done something
really important, it's not documented.
Did you hear what I said?
It's not documented. But against all
odds, when it took courage and bravery
to lead a people, a woman showed up. Her
name Deborah.
The Bible said, and the whole of Israel
She In fact, she had a tree. They called
it the tree of Deborah. The whole of
Israel will go to her to judge them.
Because she decided that I'm going to go
against the tides, against so One of the
things I've realized in my study, my
observation, is that see, when it comes
to this marriage thing, the vision does
not always come from the man.
I will give you a typical example, Joyce
Meyer.
How many of you know Joyce Meyer?
Have you read their story? Do you know
her husband?
So, the part of their story I've read
many years ago.
David Meyer was praying. He said, "God,
send me a woman that needs help."
And at that point, Joyce Meyer was in a
mess. She had gone through series of
abuses. Her husband were beating her,
and it was a mess. She needed fixing at
time. She had the call of God on her
life.
But then, she needed a helpmate.
According to scriptures, this one was
praying God sent me a woman that needs
help. This woman was praying that God, I
need a man that can help me carry this
burden.
Today, they should be in their 80s now,
right?
So, who says that division must always
come from the man?
Let me give you another example.
How many of you know Jochebed in the
Bible?
Who is Who was Jochebed?
Not father, mother.
Who said that the boy
was
uh was a perfect child? Who said that?
The mother.
Who Who orchestrated
the deliverance of Moses from
uh from the uh from the verdict of
Pharaoh?
Who did it? The mother. Who went and
became a midwife to her own son?
The mother.
She so much indoctrinated Moses.
So, you know, when you read about the
Jews that they knew usually wean their
sons around 5 years.
So, that means that technically she had
5 years access to Moses as the
caregiver.
Amen.
And in the 5 years, she made sure she
indoctrinated
the guy. When he became 40, he knew that
even though he was raised as a prince,
he was not an Egyptian.
Did somebody get what I said? So,
because many times we confuse these
things. So, we feel oh, it has to be the
man. And I'm talking to the male folks.
See, if God gives your wife a vision, it
is to your own advantage, yo.
Is somebody getting me?
So, like I said, we will never know that
there is a man called Lapidoth
or there was a man called Lapidoth if
not because there was a woman called
Deborah.
This woman was so brave, she led the
army to a war.
The king said,
"Barak, Barak the commander because he
didn't have a king there." The commander
of the army said, "Ah, you will go with
us." So, he said, "I will go, but the
glory will go to a woman."
Is somebody getting me? We need more
women like Deborah, like Esther
who will stand their ground. And I'm
glad that we are having it.
Do you know that of the commercial banks
we have today, we have about 10 CEOs who
are women?
Amen, somebody.
And in the post church post modern world
we are entering into the next 30 years,
let me tell you, there may be more women
in the workforce the corporate world
than men. There may. I'm It's just It's
a projection because if you look at it,
so there are more opportunities for a
woman to excel today than it was 10, 15,
20 years ago.
Is somebody getting me? So, the
encouragement is we can't keep being on
the receiving side and losing sight of
the
the call of God on our lives to deliver
our generation.
Your manhood and your womanhood are your
best gifts to the world.
So, what has God called you to do as a
man?
What has God called you to do as a
woman? That assignment is more important
than whether eventually you enter into
the next phase, whether there is
wifehood or husbandhood.
You may not have control over that.
Amen, somebody.
So, you cannot allow what you don't have
control over to then stop you from
maximizing what you can control.
Is somebody there?
You cannot afford
to allow what you cannot control
to take charge, to subdue, to dominate
what you can control. What you can
control is your responsibility.
Are we on the same page?
Is somebody getting me tonight?
Are we on the same page? So, your
assignment is very critical. If you have
not found it, please do everything. God,
why am I here?
Why am I here?
Man or no man, woman or no woman.
It's very critical.
There are a lot of problems around us.
And you know the interesting thing, see,
one of the things I've also been
learning in my walk with God
is that in seeking the ultimate, right,
pay attention to the to the ones God has
revealed to you.
Many times, you know, we just pray,
"God, I want to discover my purpose."
Your purpose is in your daily
assignment.
How you do one thing is how you do
everything.
He that is faithful in little is
faithful in much. Did somebody hear what
I said? He that is faithful in little is
If you cannot build yourself and grow
and become an authority where you
already are, you are going to stay there
for a long time.
I remember I was having a conversation
with her one of my procedures many years
ago, you know, so she was with her, you
know, staying with her parents, and she
would call me and say, "Pastor, I'm even
tired. I want to leave this place. I
don't know what to do."
And then she said, "My mom has come
again."
And then I asked her a question or I
said something to her. I said,
"Your parent represent a system."
And I said, "You don't fight against a
system that nurture you. You outgrow
it."
Should I say that again?
You don't fight against a system that
nurtures you. You outgrow it.
When you outgrow a system, naturally,
the door to the next level will open for
you.
The reason you are finding it very
difficult to come out of that place,
that space where you are right now, is
because you have not outgrown the
system. You don't fight it. You just
grow. Once you grow, naturally, the
system will push you out.
And I see many of us, even when you have
grown outgrown something, you are
fighting hard to stay in a place where
you should have left many years ago.
Fighting hard.
So, as you position yourself and do the
things that you can do with as much
excellence as you can, then the next
level opens up.
Who knows what that will be, what that
will mean for you?
So, pay attention to your assignment.
Very critical. The next one, authority.
Let's read 1 Corinthians 11.
1 Corinthians 11,
verse 3 to 9 from the Message
translation.
1 Corinthians 11, verse 3 to 9 in the
Message translation.
In a marriage relationship, there's
authority from Christ to husband and
from husband to wife.
The authority of Christ is the authority
of God. Any man who speaks with God or
about God, now, look at that. Any man
who speaks with God or about God in a
way that shows a lack of respect for the
authority of Christ dishonors Christ. In
the same way, a wife who speaks with God
in a way that shows a lack of respect
for the authority of her husband,
dishonors her husband. Worse, she
dishonors herself, an ugly sight like a
woman with her head shaved. This is
basically the origin of these customs we
have of women wearing head coverings in
worship while men take their hats off.
By this symbolic hat, men and women who
far too often butt their heads with each
other, submit their heads to the head
God.
From many years ago when I read this
place, I keep asking questions.
Is this thing about wearing cap or not
wearing cap?
I was raised in Methodist Church.
So, every time I read it, I say, "Look
at
from bishop, from archbishop, the
prelate,
they all wear caps.
And these people have PhD in theology.
So, if prelate is coming to church and
is wearing cap, and the Bible says,
"The man, don't cover your head." But,
the man that is teaching us is covering
his head.
I said, "God, there must be a
determining to this thing.
There must be a determining."
And then,
you know, I read a book many years back,
No Longer Two, by Bro. William Branham.
Um if you can get that book, it's a
very, very good book. It's a very good
resource, No Longer Two. And he was
saying something about headship.
That was where I first got the meaning
before I discovered it in Message
Translation.
So, it said, "In a marriage
relationship,
for a man
to minister to God and to people in the
name of God, that man must be under the
authority of Christ. So, he does not
need any covering because Christ is his
covering.
Did you hear what I said? Because Christ
is his covering, he does not need any
covering.
But for a woman who is married
who is married, so she said he said as
if the man then acts in a way that
dishonors Christ.
That means that he has left his covering
as a man and he no longer has the right,
he no longer has the authority, he no
longer has the privilege to minister in
the name of Christ. He cannot be
Christ's representative, Christ's
ambassador, if you are not under the
authority of Christ.
And he said, "For a woman that is
married,
you dishonor your own husband if you are
not under the covering of your husband.
So, your you covering your head is a
signi- signifies
that you are under the authority of your
husband."
Are you getting me? And he said, "If you
are going to speak to God and for God,
you cannot afford to dishonor your
husband."
So, the question is, "What about the
singles?"
So, if you pay attention to that,
for the single lady,
then you also qualify to be that man.
Amen.
So, for you to speak for God,
to speak with God and for God, you must
be under the authority of Christ.
Are we on the same page? What happened
in the Garden of Eden was that see, it
was called prison.
You were given authority to look after
a space, a country, to guard a
territory, and then another person
instructed you against
your king.
And then you did what the enemy asked
you to do. What did you just do?
Treason. You know what Satan told Jesus
in Matthew chapter 4 and Luke chapter 4.
He said, "All these as what?"
Complete it. As what?
"Been given to me." Who gave it?
Adam.
How?
By changing the line of command.
So,
let's ask ourselves. Because there are
many things as you are asking questions,
can I not do this? Can I do this? What
is God telling you personally?
What is it because we are Christians. Is
somebody getting me? As you are trying
to rationalize what is right or what is
wrong, the question is what is the Holy
Spirit telling you personally?
When you say you are ministering to God
and for God, are you under the covering
of Christ?
Do you obey what Christ is telling you
to do as a person?
Or it is what your favorite influencer
say you should do that you are doing?
Remember what the the second question
God asked.
Who told you?
Hello.
So, so who told you?
Who told you? Because you need to
understand
the the who is inspiring what they are
teaching you.
Is somebody getting me? You need to pay
attention. What are they telling you?
What are they teaching you? What is the
source of this information you are
consuming.
Before you say, "Oh, uh but this person
did it." Who is this person and what is
the source of that inspiration?
Who told you?
Are we on the same page? So, pay
attention. What is the Holy Spirit
telling you?
We are not going to come here as a
church and bring hammer and say, "You,
you did this. Oh, we'll break your
head." We will Nobody is going to do
that. But one of the things we teach
ourselves as a church is to mature to
the point where you can hear God for
yourself.
You can hear God for yourself. All those
questions you are asking about you The
Holy Spirit has told you what to do. You
are just looking for one pastor to
ratify it.
Pastor, can I? It's a lie. The Holy
Spirit already told you. Uh but pastor
has said, uh is pastor Holy Spirit?
Because you must grow and remain under
the covering, under the authority of
Christ.
Are we on the same page?
So, what is Christ telling you
personally? Colossians 3:16, let the
word of Christ dwell in you richly.
Let's read that, please. Colossians
3:16.
Let's read that, please.
Let the word of Christ dwell in you
richly. If you can, just display any any
version you have.
Display any version you have. Colossians
3:16.
Okay. See, let the message about Christ
in all its richness fill your lives.
Teach and counsel each other with all
the wisdom it gives. Sing psalms and
hymns and spiritual songs to God with
thankful hearts.
With thankful hearts, let the message of
Christ fill your hearts richly, richly.
Soak yourself in the word.
Because the reason why you are having
doubts and you are questioning many
things is because it is
What's the name the name of your
influencer again? It is the word that
you have in your heart. It is not the
word of Christ.
And it is the person's word that fills
your heart that you will obey.
Amen, somebody.
So, who are you listening to? Who is
talking to you?
When Eve spoke, talked, focused on Satan
long enough, she saw something she was
not supposed to see.
Are we on the same page? So, whoever is
inspiring what you are hearing will
determine your action eventually.
And that will determine your output also
eventually.
So, pay attention.
Then the third thing as we wrap up.
What did I call it for you? Can you
remember? I said the first thing was
what? Assignment, authority, and
accountability.
Right. Let's read
Um
let's have a verse again.
Accountability.
Let's read Proverbs 16:25.
And then I will read 2 Corinthians 4:18.
Proverbs 16:25, The Passion Translation,
2 Corinthians 4:18.
Before every person,
there's a path that seems like the right
one to take, but it leads straight to
hell.
2 Corinthians 4:18.
Because we don't focus our attention on
what is seen, but on what is unseen. For
what is seen is temporary, but the
unseen realm is eternal.
So, this thing, accountability.
One of the questions we need to always
ask ourselves is, what is the long-term
effect of this action I want to take
today?
When the feeling has waned,
oh I must have this.
If I don't have it, I will die.
But you've not had it for more than 30
years, you did not die.
Right? So,
if I But what is the long-term effect?
You know,
while I was preparing for this, I
remembered this
this
formula for compound interest. Right?
The future value of money, FV is equal
to PV into 1 plus R raised to power N.
Right? Now, R is the rate of
appreciation
and N is the number of years time.
Now, think about it.
Anything that is done outside of God is
a depreciating asset.
Should I say that again? Anything you do
or achieve or accomplish or become
outside of God is a depreciating asset.
It may look like the talk of town, but
it's only for a while.
There is a way that seems right.
There's a way that seems right, but the
end is what?
Is destruction.
It seems right to you, but can we look
at it
in another 10 years, another 15 years?
Will it still be right?
Are we on the same page? So,
when we look at our actions and
everything we do from a futuristic point
of view, then we are able to ask
ourselves, what is the rate? Is this
rate appreciating or depreciating?
Are we together?
Is it Is it appreciating
or depreciating?
Whatever you achieve, accomplish, become
outside of God is a depreciating asset.
Give it time.
You may look as oh, we are successful.
We are this, we are that, but just pay
attention over time. You know, every
time I I think about this Joseph guy, I
I just look at his story is just very,
very interesting.
Now, if Joseph had settled for Madam
Potiphar.
Now, in our world today, many of us will
say you don't hammer.
Imagine someone rolling out with Madam's
boss, CEO, you know,
um GM, and then you're rolling. The guy
was He was good.
Are we together? The guy was good.
The guy was He was just good. But, think
about it.
Just think about it.
Someday Potiphar is going to find out.
It might be 5 years, and it might be 5
hours.
>> [laughter]
>> But, someday Potiphar is going to find
out. What do you think Potiphar will do
to that guy?
He's going to Potiphar is going to show
up on his head.
Right? So, but it looked like an
accomplishment
that you have suffered all this while.
Eventually, the people that matter don't
notice you.
Me and Madam, me and God.
Right? You're rolling. You know, so it
it looks like a good compensation for
all these years of suffering, but that
was not God's ultimate.
The future value of the action.
Joseph said, "How can I do this
and sin against God?"
And one of the things I found out just
before your breakthrough, there will
always be
there will always be uh Satan's present.
Always just before breakthrough, Satan
will always present something. Watch it.
Before God asked Adam uh
God brought Eve.
The God said, "Name all the animals."
Chimpanzee came.
He said, "And there's chimpanzee, get
out." Baboon came. Looked like man. No,
no, get out. Uh gorilla came. You find
that one. That one
this one. Get out. The Bible says, "And
Adam found none
that looked like him." God said, "You
have passed the test."
Then now says, "Now sleep." And then
when he brought his he said, "Aha! Now
you are talking. You see? This is now
the bone of my bone." What? Just before
the breakthrough, there will be an
option that is not from God. Watch it.
Watch it.
It will look like a good compensation
for your years, but it is going to take
you many years backward.
So it will then be that all these years
of waiting, everything wasted. Why?
Because you did not wait just long
enough
for God to bring his own.
That's very critical.
So as we look at this subject,
God is interested in your status and he
wants to use you as his voice for his
generation. But the point is will you
make it about you or you will make it
about the kingdom?
No matter where you are now, there are
many other people who are like you, who
need courage, who need comfort, who need
who need support.
Why don't you be that shoulder
that your tribe can lean on?
Why don't you be that fortress that your
tribe can run to?
You might not be there forever. [snorts]
You might not be there for for longer
than you thought it would take.
But, you are there for a season and for
a reason.
And as many people are going through
that same pain, asking questions,
God is also asking you, "What are you
going to do about it?"
My prayer is that God will find each of
us worthy
to be his voice
in this in the midst of the darkness, in
the midst of the noise.
And that we will be his worthy
ambassadors
in the name of Jesus.
I want us to read a Bible verse and
we'll pray.
Just a short prayer.
Psalm 46:1. We're closing with that.
Psalm 46:1.
AMPC.
Can we read it together like a choir? 1
God is our refuge and strength, mighty
and impenetrable to temptation, a very
present and well-proved help in trouble.
God is our refuge and strength.
Can you pray to God for strength
tonight?
I don't know where you are.
I don't know what he has said to you. I
don't know
uh the struggles, the battles you've
been having.
But, can you ask him, "God,
you are my very present help.
Lord, I need your help. Lord, help me.
Lord, help me.
There's one prayer God will always
answer.
It is a prayer for help.
Can you receive help tonight?
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
Thank you, Jesus.
Thank you, Jesus. Thank you, Lord.
There's a song coming to my to my
spirit. I want us to take it together.
We can we can just rise.
Um praise team, can you help me? He is
able
more
than able
to accomplish what concerns
me today.
>> [snorts]
>> He is able,
more
than
able.
He can handle [singing]
anything that comes my way.
He is
able,
more
than
able
>> [singing]
>> to do much more
>> than I
could ever
dream.
He is
able,
he is
more
than
able. He can make me
to make me what he wants
me to be. Let's take that last line
again. He's able.
He's able.
More than
able
to do
to do much more
>> [singing]
>> than I can ever dream.
He's able. He's able.
He's able.
More
than able.
Oh, yes, he can make
me
to make me what [singing] he wants
>> [music]
>> me to be.
Father Lord,
this is our confession tonight.
Lord, you know our pains. You know our
[music] struggles.
And we know you are more than able
to accomplish your assignment
in us in spite of our frailties and our
failures.
Lord,
walk through each one of us tonight.
Help us to overcome that weakness
that is threatening to take us out of
alignment with you.
And Lord, shine your light upon us
again.
Help us to discover you afresh
in Jesus' name.
Amen. Can I pray for someone in this
service?
You know that your walk with God is not
right.
Can you just put your hand on your
heart? Let me just pray with you. Put
your hand on your chest. If you are
online, our officials will drop a link.
Put your hand on your heart also. You
want to say, "Pastor, I'm making a
commitment today. I want to focus on my
assignment. I want to align myself with
Christ authority and be accountable for
each day [music] of my life.
Can you put your hands? Make that
commitment tonight. Just make that
commitment tonight.
Make that commitment tonight. I want to
ask God to come into your heart afresh.
Make that commitment tonight.
Let me pray for you. Father, thank you
for everyone saying this prayer.
Lord, I ask oh God that you will reach
out to them in the name of Jesus.
Holy Spirit, I pray that you would
inspire each one
and you will bring them back to
alignment with you
>> [music]
>> in the name of Jesus.
If you your hand is on your heart, can
you say with me, Lord Jesus,
I've heard your word again tonight.
I pray that you forgive me.
Accept me into the beloved.
I accept you as my Lord and savior.
Thank you for answering my prayer
in Jesus name. [music]
Amen. Can we clap for our love friends
who said that prayer? Thank you, Jesus.
If you said the prayer, officials gave
you a card and if you are online, we
dropped a link in the chat room and we
trust God for each one of us that God
will make us the light he wants us to be
to our world in Jesus name. God bless
you. Let's receive the praise team.
E-Star Raising Role Models